( blowing noisemakers )
ALL:
Happy Birthday!
Come on.
Rach, come on.
Rach...
It's your birthday.
Hey.
She's not as pretty
as she was
when she was 29.
Miss Green would like
to establish some ground rules
before she comes out.
She would appreciate it
if you didn't use the words
"old" or "downhill"
or "they still look
pretty damn good."
They do!
Rachel...
come on out!
Monica made
breakfast.
Chocolate chip pancakes!
We've got presents.
Good ones?
They all came from the list
you handed out to us
two weeks ago.
Well, can I keep the presents
and still be 29?
Come on, Rach.
Look, turning 30's
not that big a deal.
Oh, really?
Is that how you felt
when you turned 30?
Why, God, why?
We had a deal.
Let the others grow old, not me.
( sobbing )
Oh, come on, you guys,
is it just me?
Am I overreacting to this?
No, Rach, it's not just you.
My 30th birthday certainly
wasn't that much fun.
And now
Chandler.
We're all
getting so old.
Why are you
doing this
to us?
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's D.O.A. ♪
♪ It's like you're always
stuck in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been
your day, your week ♪
♪ Your month,
or even your year ♪
♪ But I'll be there for you ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me, too. ♪
Rach, you're in
a great place
in your life.
You have an
amazing job,
good friends.
Yeah.
Your roommate's
a soap opera star.
Your character's in a coma.
I promised myself
I wasn't going to cry
at this one.
RACHEL:
Look, you know
I know my life's
going pretty well
but I look around
and I just see
so many people
who have accomplished
so many of their goals
by the time they're 30.
Yeah, but you shouldn't
compare yourself to me.
Come on, Phoebe!
You can do it,
Phoebe!
Come on,
Phoebe,
come on.
There you go!
( cheering )
Yay!
Whoo-hoo!
There you go.
I did it!
Look, one mile on a hippity-hop.
Ha-ha! That's it.
That's everything I wanted to do
before I was 30.
Oh! Except I wanted to patch
things up with my sister.
Oh, well, but... yay!
( cheering )
PHOEBE:
And-and girls--
this thing
is a godsend
if you know
what I mean.
( whooping )
Whoo.
Come on, let's have
some fun, huh?
What do you want to do today?
Nothing. I don't want
to do anything.
Doing nothing on your 30th
is better than
doing something stupid...
like Ross.
Hey, that was
a practical purchase.
I needed that car
for transportation, okay?
I-I have a child.
How hot do I look in this,huh?
Ross,
a sports car?
Wouldn't it have
been cheaper
to just stuff a sock
down there?
That's not what this
is about, okay?
I-I am a sports
car enthusiast.
I've always
been into cars.
Hey, what's...
the horsepower
on this thing?
I don't know,
but-but look how shiny.
I can't believe
you bought this.
Hey, could I have a ride, stud?
Hop in.
Get ready for
the smoothest
ride of your life.
( engine revving )
( tires squeaking )
Damn it!
Okay, who's next?
You know what?
I am going to do
something today.
I'm not just
going to sit around
like some old lady.
I'm going to get
something pierced... mm-hmm.
Like my, uh...
like my nose or my tongue,
or something.
Really? 'Cause, you know,
that hurts.
So what? You know what,
the way I see it...
Ow! Son of a bitch!
TAG:
Look, Rachel.
I know what
you're going through.
I'm totally freaked out
about turning 25.
Get out... get out
of my apartment.
MONICA:
All right, Rach,
for what it's worth
I think that you're doing great.
I mean, you know, let's face it.
No one handles this well.
Hmm, least
of all you.
Hmm.
JOEY:
Ah...
Would you put
that back on?
Monica's going to be here
any minute.
But it hurts
my Joey's apple.
Okay, for the last time--
it's not named after
each individual man.
You've done a
wonderful job with
this party, Chandler.
Everything looks
so lovely.
Oh, well, not
as lovely as you.
I mean, I can't believe
that you would have
a 30-year-old daughter.
And you, I can't believe
that you would have
a tux that's
30 years old.
It's older than that.
Ross was actually conceived
right near this tuxedo.
Oh.
Okay, everybody hide.
I saw her; she's coming.
Okay, okay.
Everybody down.
Everybody down!
( loud fumbling noise )
( noise ceases )
Okay, everybody stay here.
I will find out what's going on.
Hey!
You got the door open!
Hey-hey,
are you drunk?
No.
( laughs )
Okay.
Whoa!
See...
see, I wa... I was a little
nervous about turning...
thirty.
Huh.
So, the busboys
took me out
for some drinks.
I'm going to puke
on you later.
Okay, here's the thing.
We have thrown
a very formal surprise party
for you in there.
All your friends
are in there
and your parents.
No!
Yes!
Oh, no, my parents
have never seen me drunk.
That they know of.
Okay, here's the thing.
We're going to get
you some coffee
and they will never
know that you're drunk.
Really? You promise?
Yes. I'll take care of it.
Mmm, I love you
so much.
Okay.
We have to do something
about your breath.
What about
your breath?
That's still
yours.
Okay, now remember
it's a surprise party
so when you go in,
act surprised.
Okay.
Okay. Shh.
Ready?
Shh.
ALL:
Surprise!
( screaming )
Okay, forward, forward.
Stop!
Okay, back... stop!
Okay, forwa...
Stop, stop, stop!
Okay, okay, here's what
we're going to do, okay?
I'm going to break
into this mini-van
and put it in neutral.
You guys push it forward
so Ross can drive
out of the spot.
Okay.
Okay?
All right, here we go.
( alarm sounding )
Haul ass!
Happy 30th birthday.
Here.
It's for the child in you.
And the woman.
Happy 30th.
Right, why do you
keep saying that?
Because it's
our 30th birthday.
Yeah, no. We're
not 30, we're 31.
Okay.
Uh... wait!
Oh, it's you.
Yeah. What?
Yeah, we're
not 30, we're 31.
Nuh-uh!
Yuh-huh! That's
what it says
on my birth
certificate.
You have your
birth certificate?
Yeah. I got a big box
of family stuff
when my mom died.
Our mom.
Right. Okay.
Do you have
my birth certificate?
No. I sold it
to a Swedish runaway.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God,
we are 31.
Yeah.
I just lost a whole year
of my life.
Okay.
Your middle name is Pamela?
Yes.
Oh. I never knew mine.
Do you remember what it is?
Yes. "Phoebe."
That's my first name.
Right. Okay. Then, no.
Okay, look at that--
we made it
all the way
across the room.
You're doing great.
What's going on?
Monica's
a little drunk.
Yay! I love
drunk Monica.
Shh.
Oh, she's so much more fun
than regular Monica.
She doesn't
want her parents
to know she's drunk.
Oh. All right,
all right.
Here's what we'll do.
I'll get twice
as drunk as Monica
and then no one's even
going to notice her.
What...
What's going on?
( sighs )
Monica's wasted.
Maybe that'll
liven up this party.
Okay, will you just go help
her get changed, please?
Okay, but taking care
of a drunk, naked woman
seems like a job
for Joey.
Yep.
This one's
from me.
Ah!
It wasn't on your list,
but hopefully
you'll think it's really fun.
A scooter!
Stick to the list.
Always stick
to the list.
No! No, no, I love it.
Thank you.
CHANDLER:
Okay, open
ours next.
Open ours next.
Okay.
Now that you're a couple
we don't get two presents
from you guys?
For my last birthday,
you gave me a hug.
Okay, read the card,
read the card.
Okay.
"Happy Birthday, Grandma.
"It's better to be
over the hill...
Ah!
"than buried under it.
"All our love,
Monica and Chandler."
That's funny.
No, no, no, no...
That was a joke.
No, I know, I get it.
It's funny.
No, because you're not
a grandmother.
I know,
because to be a grandmother
you have to be married
and have children
and I don't have any
of those things.
That's why it's so funny.
I'm just going to go...
( choking up )
( door shuts )
All you had to do
was buy the card.
Okay, you know what?
I realized it was stupid
to get upset
about not having
a husband and kids.
All I really needed
was a plan.
See, I want to have three kids.
Well, let me guess--
and you want to have them
all at the same time
for your brother.
As I was saying...
I should probably have
the first of the three kids
by the time I'm 35, right?
Which gives me five years.
Oh.
So if I want to have a kid
when I'm 35
I don't have to get pregnant
until I'm 34
which gives Prada four years
to start making
maternity clothes.
Oh, wait, but...
now, I do want to be married
for a year
before I get pregnant.
Really! That long?
Look all you want,
it's happening.
So I don't have to get married
until I'm 33.
That's three years!
That's three whole years!
Oh, wait a minute, though--
I'll need a year-and-a-half
to plan the wedding...
and I'd like to know the guy
for, like, a year,
year-and-a-half
before we get engaged...
which means I need to meet
the guy by the time I'm 30...
Which is fine,
because you just turned...
twenty-eight!
No, Ross, no!
It is not fine!
According to my plan
I should already be with the guy
that I'm gonna marry!
TAG:
Woo-hoo!
Mmm!
Will you quit hogging it!
Oh, I'm telling you
it's like watching Bambi
learn how to walk.
You're drunk.
( both giggling )
Mom and Dad
are gonna be mad.
Maybe I'm a little drunk now.
Hey, are those crab cakes?
Yeah.
Did I not tell you
to come straight to me
when more crab cakes
were ready?
Okay...
How you feeling?
You are so handsome!
Mmm!
I want to make love to you
right here, right now!
( growls )
I really wish that you wouldn't.
Now all you have to do
is just get through a
little bit more, okay?
Then we can put
you in bed, okay?
Just smile and don't
talk to anyone.
Speech! Speech!
Let's hear
from the birthday girl, huh?
Pheebs!
You see, everybody's
looking at me.
The plan's working.
I didn't even have to
take off my top yet.
Speech!
Come on, Monica!
CROWD:
Speech! Speech!
Hey, Chandler,
you can't
keep your hands off her
for one second!
Oh, I think
it's nice.
I think it's
necessary.
I-I-I want to thank you all
for coming--
my family and my friends.
Woo... hoo!
I'd really like to say
that I'm, um...
you know what
I'd really like to say?
I'm drunk!
That's right, Mom and Dad
your little Harmomica
is hammered!
And guess what?
I've been drunk before.
( laughing )
And I've smoked a cigarette.
But you know what?
You know what?
( laughing ):
It's all okay.
It's okay
because I turned 30 today
and I can do anything I want...
( laughing )
because I... am a grown-up.
Oh, quick...
quick, help me get this off.
Yeah!
I lost a whole year!
I can believe it!
This is so unfair!
Come on, Pheebs,
it'll be okay.
Will it? Will it?
How would you feel
if you found out you were 31?
That's not gonna happen-- no--
because we have a new deal.
Plus, it totally ruined
my schedule.
I haven't done any of the things
I wanted to do
by the time I was 31.
Like what?
Like, okay, I-I...
I haven't met
any Portuguese people
I... I haven't had
the perfect kiss
and I haven't been
to sniper school.
Phoebe, you know what?
Why don't we just go upstairs
and have some birthday cake.
No, I just feel like being
by myself for awhile, all right?
I'll see you guys later. Thanks.
Oh, poor Pheebs.
Hey, you know what,
you guys?
I think I'm going
to go walk her home.
Okay.
Oh, man!
What?
He's gonna eat the cake!
Pheebs!
Wait up.
Listen, uh...
Close your eyes.
Maybe that's one thing
you can cross off your list.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, and plus,
I'm one-sixteenth Portuguese.
Oh!
Okay, is everybody clear?
We're gonna pick it up...
and move it.
Now, all we need
is teamwork, okay?
We're gonna lift
the car...
and slide it out.
Lift...
and slide.
Ross, I really
don't think--
Lift...
and slide.
Okay, here we go.
ROSS:
All right, everyone--
Lift...
and slide!
Hey, Joey...
Aw, come on, Rach,
my turn just started!
Actually, I just want
to talk to Tag.
Oh. Okay.
Hey! Can I ride this outside?
Whatever, okay?
I'm not your mother.
Not in the street!
Yeah!
Hi. Hi.
Hey.
How you doing?
You feeling any better?
Yeah, I'm doing okay.
I'm... um...
Let's talk.
Okay.
Um...
What's up?
Uh... Tag, um...
you're such a great guy
and we have so much fun
together, but I don...
Wait...
I think I see
where you're going.
But before you say
anything else, can I just
say one more thing?
Well said...
and a good example of the fun
I was referring to...
Uh... but...
( nervous chuckle )
I just think
I'm past the point
where I can, you know,
just have fun.
Rachel, don't do this.
This is just because
you're turning 30.
Yeah, it is.
But you're just a kid.
I mean, you're...
you're 25.
24, actually.
Oh, God.
You know what I wish?
I wish you were
six years older.
Well, actually,
if I'm wishing for stuff
I actually wish
I was six years younger.
Me, too.
Yeah. I'm sorry.
Hey. How'd it go?
Oh... if I only want two kids
can I keep him for another year?
You did
the right thing.
( groans )
I don't like this anymore.
Well, here we are, just
a bunch of 30-year-olds.
Do you realize,
in ten years, we're
going to be 40?
Why, God?
Why are you
doing this to us?
Yes! My baby's
finally free!
All right!
Start it up!
Let's go!
( engine starts )
Hoo-hoo!
How hot are we?
( turns off engine )
You want to buy a car?